Marlboro's Designer
In Marlboro's Designer, you can express various fabrics through textiles and physical attributes.
First, click on a fabric and drag it to the physical attribute bar at the bottom of the attribute editor.
You can see that Marlboro's Designer has a rich array of fabrics for your reference and use.
The new version of Marlboro's Designer has canceled the fabric preview.
You can check the preview effect of the fabric and drag it to the bar at the top window and fabric.
Preview fabric allows you to quickly find the general feeling of the fabric.
You can use these fabrics directly, or you can use these preview fabrics to create the fabric you want.
Open the details bar at the bottom of the preview bar.
You can see that the physical attribute details of the fabric are in the direction of the gold line, the tail line and the left and right smallest line.
Each of the four lines is controlled by the same attribute.
You can drag and move the slider to adjust the value of each direction separately.
When you create a new version, the gold line is defaulted to the value direction, and the tail line is the 90-degree angle direction of the gold line.
The tail line is defaulted to the 45-degree angle direction.
You can check the gold line direction at any time through the 2D window and the 3D window.
Or adjust the gold line direction to keep it vertical.
Let's go back to the fabric details.
Here we can make more detailed fabric adjustments.
Let's look at the gold tail sand strength and the tail line strength first.
This group is controlled.
This group is controlled by the stretch performance of the fabric in these specific directions.
Generally speaking, the physical attribute value on the toe line is lower than the value of the gold tail sand.
The higher these values, the weaker the fabric elasticity, the less likely it is that it will become long due to gravity or pulling.
The more likely it is to produce fine, sharp wrinkles, the more wrinkly and hard it looks.
The more you stretch, the more difficult it is to make wrinkles.
As the number of these values is lower, the better the fabric elasticity, the easier it is to create wrinkles.
The more you stretch, the more difficult it is to create wrinkles.
Let's add a texture principle for the good shape pattern here.
To explain more directly the functions of the gold tail direction and the line direction.
Now the pattern direction on the top panel is parallel to the gold line direction, and then use it to represent the gold line direction.
You can see that when the simulation is not started, the gold line position on the panel is perpendicular to the ground in the 3D window.
Press the control button to simulate.
You can see that the gold line direction is still perpendicular to the ground in the middle of this piece of fabric.
And go to the left and right sides, the gold line direction gradually becomes oblique.
The gold line direction on the left and right sides of the fabric becomes almost parallel to the ground direction.
Because the radius of this top panel is the same everywhere, and the strength of the gold edge sand is the same as the strength of the angle line.
So its bottom is now completely flat.
If we now increase the strength of the gold edge sand,
You can see the length in the middle.
It's obviously shorter and tighter.
Because the fabric will be more elastic in the direction of the gold sand, it is not easy to be affected by gravity and stretched before.
It will become shorter in the direction of the gold sand.
And its left side is actually more elastic in the direction of the left and right sides.
The strength of the main resistance to gravity is not changed, so there is no obvious change.
In the same way, we can adjust the detail value in the individual direction.
Let's control the fold on the top panel.
The strength of the button of the top panel, which is moving on the top and bottom, is driving the top panel in a vertical direction.
It is easy to see the fold at the bottom of the top panel is getting more and more detailed.
The fold at the bottom of the top panel is getting more and more detailed.
This is because the fabric is tightened on the horizontal axis, so it is getting shorter, which means that the fold is dare to enter the straight direction.
Returning to the original state.
The strength of the golden sand in the top panel is being increased by itself.
You can see that the fold at the bottom is not obvious, and there are some horizontal folds at the shoulders.
This is because the shirt is shortened in the vertical direction, which causes more horizontal folds.
Let's go back to the original state.
If we want the fold at the left side of the shirt to be more obvious,
which direction should we raise the number?
The direction of the left diagonal line.
You can see that the fold becomes obvious.
Next is the curve intensity group.
The higher the curve intensity, the better the support force of the fabric.
It is easier to loosen when simulated, and the fold is less, wider and rounder.
Let's go back to the original state.
The lower the curve intensity, the worse the support force of the fabric.
It is easier to collapse when simulated, and the fold is more, narrower and flat.
Let's try it on the shirt.
The higher the curve intensity, the more the support force of the fabric.
The fold becomes less, wider and rounder.
The fabric looks more broad and thick.
Let's go back to the original state.
The lower the curve intensity, the more the support force of the fabric.
It is easier to loosen when simulated, and the fold is more, narrower and rounder.
The fold is more, narrower and flat.
It is easier to collapse when simulated, and the fold is more, narrower and flat.
The fold is more, narrower and rounder.
The fold is very good.
The shorter the curve intensity, the narrower the support force of the fabric.
The EVENT RAPPilarity is used to Blacked the fold.
Blacked the fold.
Had theTYPE Cit∆K admit the dress size and the type of the fold.
It controls the degree to which the bending strength within the frame range is reduced.
Therefore, the deformation rate is strongly related to the deformation strength, and the bending strength is also closely related.
Just like this small mountain peak in front of you.
The top of the mountain is the most powerful place for folding and deformation.
The tension of the deformation rate is controlled by this invisible cover.
From the top of the mountain to the corner of the mountain, it extends and covers the bending range.
The larger the value, the larger the bending range of the extension and control of the bending range.
Most of the time, we will adjust the deformation rate to 60, which is about half of the range.
The deformation rate of 100 is a very special value.
It controls the bending strength of the mountain.
From the top of the mountain to the corner of the mountain.
When the deformation strength and bending strength are also low enough, the whole mountain can be completely flattened.
We can try it here.
You can see that after the deformation rate is set to 100, the fold of the sewing line is completely flattened.
Next is the deformation strength.
The tension of the deformation strength is controlled within the range of the deformation rate.
The bending strength of the fabric will be multiplied by the deformation strength, and the reduction will be lower.
For example, at this time, the deformation strength of 100 is 100% of the bending strength within the deformation range.
At this time, the fabric of the folding number will remain the same shape as other fabrics.
Nothing will change.
The smaller the deformation strength, the more the bending strength will be reduced.
The stronger the folding number, the weaker the support of the fabric.
When we adjust the deformation strength to 20.
At this time, the deformation rate is controlled within the range of the fabric.
The real bending strength is 20% of the bending strength set in front.
At this time, I will simulate it again.
You will find that the fabric at the peak of the fold is clearly down.
Usually, we only use a fixed number to adjust the deformation strength to 20 or 80.
To control the fold that has already been made, it becomes a little firmer or rounder.
The weight function is translated as density in the previous version.
This column controls the weight of the fabric.
The heavier the weight, the easier the fabric will be stretched by gravity.
It will also be less likely to float around and feel better.
When we need a piece of clothing that looks good.
But we don't want it to lose its support because of its weight.
It becomes flat.
We can use the pressure function to cooperate with the weight function.
To give the clothes a little support from the inside and the outside.
Now the interaction between Marvelous Designer and Unreal Engine has become better.
When exporting the usd file.
If you select the option of clothing simulation information.
You will be able to use the super scroll function in the virtual engine.
Accept and edit many fabric parameters from Marvelous Designer.
Thank you for watching. See you in the next video.